Boardman & Seymour records
Litchfield Historical Society
Boardman & Seymour records
1794-1811
Litchfield Historical Society 7 South Street, P.O. Box 385 Litchfield, CT, 6759 URL: http://www.litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org/archon Email: archivist@litchfieldhistoricalsociety.org Phone: 860-567-4501 Fax: 860-567-3565
Seymour, Moses, 1774-1826; Boardman, Elijah, 1760-1823
3.00
The Boardman & Seymour Records (2009-75-0) consist of correspondence, bills, legal documents, licenses to sell liquor, orders, receipts, statements of accounts and other business records. Daniel Boardman (1757-1833), New York City businessman and merchant, his brother Elijah Boardman (1760-1823), New Milford businessman and merchant, and Moses Seymour Jr. (1774-1826), Litchfield merchant and town official, maintained a partnership to operate a store in Litchfield in which they sold "a variety of Dry and West-India Goods, suitable for all seasons; consisting of almost every article usually retailed in a Country Store," according to a Dec. 17, 1794, advertisement in the Litchfield Monitor. The partnership was dissolved in 1804, according to a Nov. 21 newspaper advertisement.
2009-75-0
Biographical Note
Moses Seymour was born at Litchfield, Conn., June 30, 1774, died there May 8, 1826, aged 52. He married Mabel Strong in Addison, Vt., on May 29, 1782 and they had nine children. He was a merchant in Litchfield; postmaster for 25 years; sheriff for six years.
Scope and Contents
The Boardman & Seymour Records (2009-75-0) consist of correspondence, bills, legal documents, licenses to sell liquor, orders, receipts, statements of accounts and other business records. Daniel Boardman (1757-1833), New York City businessman and merchant, his brother Elijah Boardman (1760-1823), New Milford businessman and merchant, and Moses Seymour Jr. (1774-1826), Litchfield merchant and town official, maintained a partnership to operate a store in Litchfield in which they sold "a variety of Dry and West-India Goods, suitable for all seasons; consisting of almost every article usually retailed in a Country Store," according to a Dec. 17, 1794, advertisement in the Litchfield Monitor. The partnership was dissolved in 1804, according to a Nov. 21 newspaper advertisement.
The records (1794-1811) document the affairs and transactions of the business and the concerns of the owners, sellers of goods, and customers and are arranged in two series, Series 1, Correspondence, and Series 2, Business records. Elijah Boardman's letters to Seymour are noteworthy as they occasionally reveal his business philosophy, his take on current business and market conditions, and his opinion of events of the day.
Arrangement of Materials
The records are arranged in two series:
Series 1: Correspondence
Series 2: Business records
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Boardman & Seymour
Genre/Form of Material:
Business records; Correspondence; Financial records; Legal documents
Geographic Name:
Litchfield (Conn.)
Topical Term:
Boardman, David Sherman, 1768-1864; License system; Merchants
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Litchfield Historical Society from George Seymour, Arthur Shaw on 04/11/1989.
Accruals
The Boardman & Seymour Records (2009-75-0) were originally part of the gift that also included the Beckwith Family Collection (1988-01-0). Staff determined that the Boardman & Seymour Records are a distinct group of records.
Other Information
This collection was processed with support from the Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR).
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Correspondence
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Boardman & Seymour, re: cheese purchase, 1804 (Folder 1)
  - Boardman & Seymour, re: Goodwin, James, 1795-1797 (Folder 2)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1794 (Folder 3)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1795 (Folder 4)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1796 (Folder 5)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1797 Jan-Apr (Folder 6)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1797 Jun-Jul (Folder 7)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1797 Aug-Dec (Folder 8)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1798 Jan-May (Folder 9)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1798 Jun-Sep (Folder 10)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1798 Nov-Dec (Folder 11)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1799 (Folder 12)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1800 Mar-Apr (Folder 13)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1800 May-Oct (Folder 14)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1801 (Folder 15)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1802 Jan-Mar (Folder 16)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1802 Apr-Nov (Folder 17)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1803 Jan-Feb (Folder 18)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, 1803 Apr-Oct (Folder 19)
  - Boardman & Seymour, incoming, [1804?] (Folder 20)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Boardman & Seymour, 1795 Jan-Feb (Folder 21)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Boardman & Seymour, 1795 Apr-May (Folder 22)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Boardman & Seymour, 1795 Jun-Oct (Folder 23)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Boardman & Seymour, 1795 Nov-Dec (Folder 24)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Boardman & Seymour, 1796 Jan-Jun (Folder 25)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Boardman & Seymour, 1796 Oct-Nov (Folder 26)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Boardman & Seymour, 1798 (Folder 27)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1794 Dec 5-11 (Folder 28)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1794 Dec 15 (Folder 29)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1795 Mar (Folder 30)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1795 Apr (Folder 31)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1795 May (Folder 32)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1795 Jun (Folder 33)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1795 Aug-Sep (Folder 34)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1795 Oct (Folder 35)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1795 Dec (Folder 36)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Jan-Mar (Folder 37)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Apr-Jun (Folder 38)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Jul (Folder 39)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Aug 4-12 (Folder 40)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Aug 13-17 (Folder 41)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Sep (Folder 42)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Oct (Folder 43)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Nov (Folder 44)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1796 Dec (Folder 45)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1797 Mar (Folder 46)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1797 Jul (Folder 47)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1797 Oct (Folder 48)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1798 Mar-Apr (Folder 49)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1798 May-Jun (Folder 50)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1799 (Folder 51)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1800 (Folder 52)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1808 Feb (Folder 53)
  - Boardman, Elijah to Seymour Jr., Moses, 1808 Jun-Sep (Folder 54)
  - Coffin, Ralph, 1803 (Folder 55)
  - Harrison, Simon, 1798 (Folder 56)
  - Huntington, Hezekiah, circa 1800 (Folder 57)
  - Seymour, Henry, 1801 (Folder 58)
  - Seymour, Henry, 1803 (Folder 59)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, 1800 (Folder 60)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, 1810 (Folder 61)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1795 (Folder 62)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1797 (Folder 63)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1798 Jan-Jun (Folder 64)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1798 Oct-Dec (Folder 65)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1799 (Folder 66)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1800 Jan-Mar (Folder 67)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1800 Apr (Folder 68)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1800 May-Jun (Folder 69)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1800 Jul (Folder 70)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1800 Oct-Nov (Folder 71)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1800 Dec 11-12 (Folder 72)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1800 Dec 13-21 (Folder 73)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1801 (Folder 74)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1802 Mar 15-18 (Folder 75)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1802 Mar 22-23 (Folder 76)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1802 Apr-Jun (Folder 77)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1802 Sep (Folder 78)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1803 Jan-Feb (Folder 79)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1803 Mar-May (Folder 80)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1803 Jul-Aug (Folder 81)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1803 Sep (Folder 82)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1803 Oct-Dec (Folder 83)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1804 Feb-Apr (Folder 84)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1804 Jun-Dec (Folder 85)
  - Seymour Jr., Moses, incoming, 1808 (Folder 86)
  - Smart, John, 1801 (Folder 87)
  - [?] to Lewis, [?], 1797 (Folder 88)
- Business records
  - Agreement, Boardman, Elijah and Doolittle, 1795 Jan 11 (Folder 1)
  - Assignment of Clark, Uziel's suit against Samuel Baldwin, 1799 Nov 25 (Folder 2)
  - Attachment against Swan, Oliver, 1808 Mar 10 (Folder 3)
  - Bills, 1794 (Folder 4)
  - Bills, 1795 (Folder 5)
  - Bills, 1795 (Folder 6)
  - Bills, 1796 (Folder 7)
  - Bills, 1797 (Folder 8)
  - Bills, 1798 (Folder 9)
  - Bills, 1799 (Folder 10)
  - Bills, 1800 (Folder 11)
  - Bills, 1800 (Folder 12)
  - Bills, 1801 (Folder 13)
  - Certificates of duties paid on geneva, 1795, 1797 (Folder 14)
    Geneva is another term for genever or jenever liquor.
  - Judgment against Bissell, Luther, 1800 Mar 31 (Folder 15)
  - Judgment against Bradley, Maj., 1798 Jul 23 (Folder 16)
  - Judgment against Clark, Uziel, 1800 Mar 28 (Folder 17)
  - Judgment against Coe, Thomas, family, 1811 Mar 14 (Folder 18)
  - Judgment against Collier, Thomas, 1806 Dec 11 (Folder 19)
  - Judgment against Gilbert, Joseph, 1802 Mar 3 (Folder 20)
  - Judgment against Hunt, Darius, 1807 Mar 10 (Folder 21)
  - Judgment against Hunt, Frederick, 1806 May 20 (Folder 22)
  - Judgment against Jacklin, Jack, 1806 May 20 (Folder 23)
  - Judgment against Moss, Elihu, 1808 Feb 7 (Folder 24)
  - Judgment against Palmer, Andrew, 1806 Dec 15 (Folder 25)
  - Judgment against Peck, Moses, 1808 Feb 8 (Folder 26)
  - Judgment against Swan, Oliver, 1799 Dec 18 (Folder 27)
  - Label, Pattilles Royales, G v P & S, circa 1800 (Folder 28)
  - License to sell foreign distilled spirits, 1794 (Folder 29)
  - License to sell foreign distilled spirits, 1795 (Folder 30)
  - License to sell foreign distilled spirits, 1797 (Folder 31)
  - License to sell foreign distilled spirits, 1799 (Folder 32)
  - License to sell foreign distilled spirits, 1800 (Folder 33)
  - License to sell foreign distilled spirits, 1801 (Folder 34)
  - License to sell wines, 1795 (Folder 35)
  - License to sell wines, 1796 (Folder 36)
  - License to sell wines, 1797 (Folder 37)
  - License to sell wines, 1799 (Folder 38)
  - License to sell wines, 1800 (Folder 39)
  - List of articles shipped on board Capt. Hubbell bound to Newfield, belonging to Boardman & Seymour, circa 1800 (Folder 40)
  - List of demands against Everett, Daniel, 1794 Dec 25 (Folder 41)
  - Orders, 1796 (Folder 42)
  - Orders, 1797 (Folder 43)
  - Orders, 1797 (Folder 44)
  - Orders, 1797 (Folder 45)
  - Orders, 1797 (Folder 46)
  - Orders, 1797 (Folder 47)
  - Orders, 1798 (Folder 48)
  - Orders, 1798 (Folder 49)
  - Orders, 1798 (Folder 50)
  - Orders, 1799 (Folder 51)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 52)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 53)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 54)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 55)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 56)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 57)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 58)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 59)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 60)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 61)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 62)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 63)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 64)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 65)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 66)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 67)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 68)
  - Orders, 1800 (Folder 69)
  - Promissory notes, 1795, 1803 (Folder 70)
  - Receipt for duty on a two-wheel carriage, Seymour Jr., Moses, 1802 (Folder 71)
  - Receipts, 1795 (Folder 72)
  - Receipts, 1796 (Folder 73)
  - Receipts, 1797 (Folder 74)
  - Receipts, 1797 (Folder 75)
  - Receipts, 1798 (Folder 76)
  - Receipts, 1798 (Folder 77)
  - Receipts, 1798 (Folder 78)
  - Receipts, 1799 (Folder 79)
  - Receipts, 1799 (Folder 80)
  - Receipts, 1800 (Folder 81)
  - Receipts, 1802 (Folder 82)
  - Reeve, Tapping records, 1797, 1800 (Folder 83)
    Four orders which have been foldered separately for convenience.
  - Statements of account, 1795 (Folder 84)
  - Statements of account, 1796 (Folder 85)
  - Statements of account, 1797 (Folder 86)
  - Statements of account, 1798 (Folder 87)
  - Statements of account, 1798 (Folder 88)
  - Statements of account, 1798 (Folder 89)
  - Statements of account, 1800 (Folder 90)
  - Statements of account, 1800 (Folder 91)
  - Statements of account, 1800 (Folder 92)
  - Statements of account, 1801 (Folder 93)
  - Statements of account, 1803 (Folder 94)
  - Statements of account, 1809 (Folder 95)
  - Miscellaneous Boardman & Seymour records, circa 1794-1808 (Folder 96)